our followers thank you very much
sleeping in the outset express my
gratitude to unit out and the horse
institute or this extremely timely
opportunity to discuss social contact
and I'm particularly happy that you walk
like this the day after this media
conference because this is a time for
stop taking this is done see how the
social contract which perhaps has been a
bitch to use it can now be built on the
basis of what we have before us dr.
Hawkins ty 919 quite reveals what he
were going to say that what he said
clearly gives me an entry into what I
was going to say and this is essentially
the veena knowledge and I think what dr.
Steiner said is absolutely right in
multilateral negotiations we become like
Jess tears who are really looking at the
moon vs accountable but I've lost sight
of the original objectives behind the
negotiations and I find it a bit
bothersome that for instance in the
conference of the parties that we are
headed it doesn't have a half off almost
we said them spend time and talking
about the original or the scientific
reason
for us to take action on climate changes
we just get bogged down through two
weeks of intense negotiations on seeing
what country he has stopped it and what
country wants AV wants be wants and so
on and I would like to submit that the
time has come for us to see that
knowledge becomes the major driver of
action that we were going to take at the
globe resembles and dr. Steiner also
referred to Gandhi I really think that
John Dee was deeply influenced by rusev
and several of the other writers who
sort of allows the modern auctions at a
time when perhaps it was in a state of
limbo and therefore i would say that
today also represents something like don
t plus 100 because he said these things
almost 100 years ago what's also
interesting is that here he was a lawyer
who began as acetic but what insect has
profound implications for economic
policy and the inclusion of ecological
considerations in the formulation of
economic policy the other person who i
believe also said something extremely
profound and far-reaching was a
biologist or
harden who in 1968 talked about the
tragedy of the Commons and I think this
is what should be one of our major areas
of himself the manner in which we are
using the global Commons doctor
diagnoses are rightly talked about
imposing a tax which perhaps the global
community should look at very seriously
for the use of global Commons because
it's everybody's what should I say
inheritance and yet it seems to be
nobody's possession so we funded it the
over use it to the extent that perhaps
we have now reached the point where we
need to work much faster and perhaps
explain much larger resources to solve
the problem then if we are done so maybe
20 or 25 years ago so we need to not
only use knowledge but also shed the
illusion of knowledge what we think
you're funny and here I'd like to put
something that job and a change said he
said the difficulty lies not in the new
ideas but an escaping from the old ones
and i think that's it was a challenge is
finding the means by which we can bridge
the gap between knowledge and its
application i personally believe that
there is really not an adequate
this is provided to the whole issue of
risk management after all human society
is missing risks the spread of poverty
is one type of residence but we are
exacerbating that condition by imposing
let's say need paxil climate change
there are going to make it almost
impossible for poor people to be able to
lift themselves out of the tension that
they arranged so I think we really need
to pay attention through the whole
objective of risk management in
development policy as in this context I
would like to say that the IPCC has
brought out two special reports in the
last year which have particular
relevance to what I'm talking about one
of them deals with extreme events in
disaster and the other deals with
renewable energy sources and climate
change mitigation so on the one hand we
are talking about these types of climate
changes which represented a major threat
for human society and all living species
and on the other we are looking at means
mention was made earlier about bringing
about the transition away from fossil
fuels well as it happens renewable
energy technologies today of one part of
the solution that should be implemented
with the sense of urgency but if you
look at it minimizing risks then they
really talking about the use of
incremental steps versus
transformational changes and the
question he should ask is in specific
conditions are small incremental steps
and often or do we need to bring about
changes because it is entirely possible
that with extreme climate and weather
events we may find it very difficult for
systems to adapt sustainably without
transformational change so I think this
is an issue that we have to build into
our development policies and therefore
we must also create the conditions by
which societies are resilient because
there will be risks there will be the
last and a fall through mitigation of
conditions of me now scat systems we
have to contain them we have been limit
them it but we really don't have a
choice other than to adapt to some
impacts that are our inevitable and
societies which happened within this
extremely important notion of resilience
in our development policies the
degradation of English systems are also
of course often something else these
provide essential services and if these
services are affected than we are
limiting the options for future risk
management and of course in all this
learning processes are extremely crucial
because unless we use knowledge we might
be doing things which are ineffective or
much too expensive so what I'm saying
that we need and interactive set of
policies that involve a tactician
mitigation as well as sustainable
development and the three are linked
together you can't have one without the
and here I have to the final part that I
would like to emphasize even though we
really haven't as many would question
not spend enough on research in
developing the science and humanity
technologies and concerns today they
costs have come down with significant
reasons so much so that in several
applications these technologies are now
competing with conventional forms of
energy suppliers and you see examples of
this all over the world now my art
institute in India is automated program
called life in the billion lives because
all of us should find it totally
intolerable that in this day and hit in
the air 2012 we rarely had 1.3 1.4
billion people who have to access to the
little schemes and if we go the
conventional route I have three more
generation you will go by without any
benefits of electricity be connected to
their homes so what we develop is a set
of solar lanterns that are low-cost that
are very light and rated and use LED
systems and we train an open in a
village to charge of all these solar
that
during the daytime using a solar panels
on the roof and she raises them out at
night do all the villages gets them
right in the morning and this is a very
market-friendly model where they
essentially taking technology for
lighting after what is electricity
required it's required for the end users
by which the human condition can be
enhanced and if we can use technology in
a way that is socially market wise
acceptable then we are really bringing
about the application of knowledge which
otherwise would remain totally beyond
the reach of people who are totally
dispossess it last point I want to make
is that all of this has happened only if
we adopt the lights and policies and
policies necessarily will have to be
forward-looking will have to be
comprehensive and broad in their suite
so that it benefits those who are wise
left out of the system and here may I
say in this special performance we
assess 164 definition values of our
renewable energy can take the share of
energy supply by 2050 and you would be
surprised that the range is very must
from a level percent of the total energy
supply in 2050 from radio and resources
to seventy-seven percent now why is
there this huge space well simply
because this is going to be dependent on
the policies that we adopt not in 20
fucking but that we